# **Tadesse Dubale**

## **FULL-STACK Ruby on Rails Engineer**

tadalem26@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | AngelList | Portfolio | HackerRank

## **SUMMARY**

Full-stack engineer with 4+ years of software development and 8+ years of chief ICT technician experience, over 15 professional certificates, algorithm and DS knowledge with <u>5-star/Gold badges</u>. Previous accomplishments include top contributor at Microverse, top software project developer at Bahir Dar University, and currently reviewing React and Ruby on Rails projects.

### **SKILLS**

- Front-End: React, Vue, jQuery, AJAX, Tailwindcss, Bootstrap, Adobe XD, Illustrator.
- Back-End: Ruby, NodeJS, Ruby on Rails.
- Database: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB,
- Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub flow, TDD, BDD, Dev Tools.
- Professional: Actively pair-programming, led developer, and developed over 50 solo projects.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Full Stack EngineerRemote, USAMICROVERSESeptember 2022 – Present

- Review 10+ ruby on rails projects a day, achieving 100% review quality, by accelerating junior developers' skill set and consistency using the criteria provided.
- Deliver objective feedback to 50+ junior developers on best practices, Git skills, clean code, etc. to foster a positive culture around reviews, hence improving collaboration and relationships.
- Apply GitHub pull requests and live pages, Linter rules, and other tools to review code quality.

## **Full Stack Web Development**

Remote

Freelancer

April 2018 – Present Yellow Rooms. — Online reservation system that enables booking available hotel rooms.

• Built with: React, Redux, PostgreSQL, and Ruby on Rails. Source Code.

Bloagers. — Web app that empowers anyone to read blogs and registered users to post/read blogs.

• Built with: JavaScript, ¡Query, PHP, and MySQL. Source Code.

<u>I spend</u>. — A mobile web app that allows registered users to manage their spending.

• Built with: Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL. Source Code.

## Chief Technical Assistant (Part-time)

Bahir Dar, Ethiopia

**Bahir Dar University** 

March 2013 - Present

- Publish two programming course laboratory manuals (web page design and basics of HTML) for Junior students to learn and grow their skills successfully throughout the program.
- Amplify the grasp of Internet usage and basic online security of 40+ staff members by delivering tech seminars on these topics.

### **EDUCATION**

### Remote Full Stack Web Development, MICROVERSE

February 2022 - August 2022

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Updated my skills in pair programming, collaboration with programmers, GitHub, and git-flow.
- Achieved monthly top contributor award.

### Bachelor Degree, Computer science, Bahir Dar University

April 2013 - November 2018

- Developed one of the **top 5** software projects of the year at Bahir Dar University.
- Scored A+ (4/4) in software project management, DS & A, OOP, distributed systems, and more.
- Led the development of a full-stack web app and acquired 2 certificates of recognition.